This month I’d like to talk
about “Presenting Your Gifts to God.”
今月のテーマは 「贈り物を
神に差し出しましょう」です
We certainly have every reason
to consider this topic.
なぜこのことを
考えるべきなのでしょうか
Well, why is that?
なぜなら エホバから
たくさん頂いたからです
It’s because Jehovah gives us so much.
ヤコブ 1:17にある通りです
James 1:17 says:
“Every good gift and every perfect present
「あらゆる良い賜物 またあらゆる
完全な贈り物は上から来ます
“is from above,
coming down from the Father
of the celestial lights.”
天の光の父から下って来るのです」
For example, Jehovah allows us
to enjoy the gift of life,
例えば エホバは命という
贈り物を与えてくださいました
even though our first parents
最初の二親はそれを
大切にしませんでしたが
tried to take that from us.
He’s provided us with a variety of foods.
また いろいろな食べ物も
与えてくださいました
The environment
is just right to support life.
生きていくための完璧に
整った環境もそうです
He’s given us his precious Word, the Bible,
神とその目的を知るための
聖書も与えてくださいました
so that we can come to know him
and his purposes.
そして最大の「完全な贈り物」は
And the greatest “perfect present”
Jehovah has given us
贖いです
is the ransom.
Jehovah sacrificed a great deal
エホバはイエスという
大きな犠牲を払って
to arrange for Jesus to buy back for us
私たちに永遠の命の
希望を与えられました
the hope of everlasting life.
エホバにはそうする義務は
ありませんでした
This was at no obligation on Jehovah’s part.
純粋に愛ゆえの贈り物なのです
It was totally a gift of love.
ご一緒にヨハネ第一 4:9を
読みましょう
Please read with me 1 John 4:9:
「これによって神の愛が
明らかにされました
“By this the love of God
was revealed in our case,
すなわち 神は⋯⋯独り子を世に遣わし
“that God sent his only-begotten Son
into the world
彼によってわたしたちが命を得られる
ようにしてくださったからです」
so that we might gain life through him.”
What a gift of love from Jehovah, our God!
神からの何と愛ある贈り物でしょう
What does that move us to do?
何をしたいと思いますか
Maybe you’ve had the experience
of a close friend or family member
おそらく皆さんも 親友や家族から
unexpectedly giving you a valuable gift.
思いがけないプレゼントを
もらったことがあるでしょう
Immediately, what are you thinking?
どんなことをすぐに考えますか
You are probably trying to think
of what you can give in return.
お返しに何をあげようか でしょう
How much more so would we want
to ‘present our gifts to God’
では 神がしてくださったことへの
心からの感謝を示すためには
so as to show our sincere appreciation
なおさら「贈り物を差し出したい」
と思うのではないでしょうか
for all he’s done!
エホバに喜ばれる贈り物
について考えましょう
Let’s consider some possible gifts
that Jehovah would be pleased
to receive from us.
このビデオをご覧の皆さんの多くは
Many of you in our viewing audience
エホバのご意志を行うために
have been moved to give your life to Jehovah,
献身した方々でしょう
dedicating yourself to do his will.
素晴らしいことです！
That’s commendable!
ローマ 12章にある通りです
That’s what Romans 12 urges us to do.
しかし エホバへの献身という形で
お返しすることを考えたことはあっても
However, there are some of you listening
who have thought about this way
of giving back to Jehovah,
まだこの重要な段階を踏んで
おられない方もいるでしょう
but you haven’t yet taken this vital step.
使徒パウロはローマ 12:1で
何を励ましていますか
Notice the appeal the apostle Paul makes
at Romans 12:1:
「そのようなわけで 兄弟たち
わたしは⋯⋯あなた方に懇願します
“Therefore, I appeal to you
by the compassions of God, brothers,
あなた方の体を 神に受け入れられる
“to present your bodies
as a living sacrifice,
生きた 聖なる犠牲として
差し出しなさい
“holy and acceptable to God,
これがあなた方の理性による
神聖な奉仕です」
a sacred service with your power of reason.”
あなたの命は貴重です
Your life is precious.
Presenting your body, your whole soul, to God
あなたの命は 差し出すことのできる
最高の贈り物です
is one of the best gifts you can give to him.